{
    "questions": [
        {
            "id": "1",
            "question": "If f(x)=5x^2+2x-3 and g(x)=x^3-1, what is the value of f(g(-2))?",
            "type": "multiple_choice",
            "options": [
                "-19",
                "-573",
                "573",
                "371"
            ],
            "correct_answer": "371",
            "whyCorrectAnswer": "Substitute -2 in place of x in g(x) to find g(-2) = -9. Then put -9 in place of x in f(x) to get f(g(-2)) = 371.",
            "difficulty": 4
        },
        {
            "id": "2",
            "question": "The functions p and q are defined as p(x) = x^2 + 4x -5 and q(x) = 2x - 1. What is the value of p(q(3))?",
            "type": "multiple_choice",
            "options": [
                "83",
                "115",
                "25",
                "36"
            ],
            "correct_answer": "25",
            "whyCorrectAnswer": "First find the value of q(3) = 2(3) - 1 = 5. Then substitute this into the p(x) equation: p(q(3)) = p(5) = 5^2 + 4*5 - 5 = 25.",
            "difficulty": 3
        },
        {
            "id": "3",
            "question": "A function m satisfies m(2)=4 and m(6)=8. A function n satisfies n(8)=16 and n(16)=32. What is the value of m(n(16))?",
            "type": "multiple_choice",
            "options": [
                "8",
                "16",
                "32",
                "4"
            ],
            "correct_answer": "8",
            "whyCorrectAnswer": "First, find the value of n(16) which equals to 32. Then find the value of m(32). Since m(6) = 8, we assume it to be linear; thus m(32) will be 8 as well.",
            "difficulty": 4
        },
        {
            "id": "4",
            "question": "The functions f and g are defined as f(x) = 1/(3x-2) and g(x) = 2x^2+7. What is the value of f(g(2))?",
            "type": "multiple_choice",
            "options": [
                "0.041",
                "24.46",
                "0.020",
                "0.520"
            ],
            "correct_answer": "0.020",
            "whyCorrectAnswer": "Calculate g(2) = 2(2)^2+7 = 15. Then put 15 into f(x) to get f(g(2)) = 1/(3*15-2) = 0.020.",
            "difficulty": 5
        },
        {
            "id": "5",
            "question": "If p(x) = x^4 - 5x^2 + 6, what is the value of p(p(2))?",
            "type": "multiple_choice",
            "options": [
                "2672",
                "532",
                "1064",
                "1344"
            ],
            "correct_answer": "2672",
            "whyCorrectAnswer": "Find p(2) = 2^4 - 5(2)^2 + 6 = 6. Then find p(p(2)) by substituting x by p(2) = p(6) = 6^4 - 5(6)^2 + 6 = 2672.",
            "difficulty": 5
        },
        {
            "id": "6",
            "question": "Given that f(x) = x^3 - 2x^2 +x - 1, if f(k) = 1, what could be the value of k?",
            "type": "multiple_choice",
            "options": [
                "2",
                "-1",
                "-2",
                "1"
            ],
            "correct_answer": "1",
            "whyCorrectAnswer": "F(1)=1^3 - 2(1)^2 + 1 - 1 = 1, which equals to 1 as asked in the original question.",
            "difficulty": 4
        },
        {
            "id": "7",
            "question": "If m(x) = 2x^3 (3x-7)^2, what is the value of m(m(-1))?",
            "type": "multiple_choice",
            "options": [
                "32",
                "1024",
                "128",
                "512"
            ],
            "correct_answer": "512",
            "whyCorrectAnswer": "First find m(-1) = 2(-1)^3(-3 - 7)^2 = -2 * 100 = -200. Then find m(-200), which will be 2(200)^3 (-600-7)^2 = 512.",
            "difficulty": 5
        },
        {
            "id": "8",
            "question": "If g(x) = x^2 - 3x + 2 and h(x) = g(g(x)), what is the value of h(1)?",
            "type": "multiple_choice",
            "options": [
                "-4",
                "0",
                "4",
                "-2"
            ],
            "correct_answer": "0",
            "whyCorrectAnswer": "First find g(1) = 1 - 3 + 2 = 0. Then find h(1) = g(g(1)) = g(0) = 0^2 - 3*0 + 2 = 0.",
            "difficulty": 3
        },
        {
            "id": "9",
            "question": "If f(x) = 3x - 1 and g(x) = x^3 + 2, what is the value of f(g(3))?",
            "type": "multiple_choice",
            "options": [
                "104",
                "78",
                "83",
                "107"
            ],
            "correct_answer": "104",
            "whyCorrectAnswer": "You can find this by first computing g(3) = 3^3 + 2 = 29. Then compute f(29) = 3 * 29 - 1 = 104.",
            "difficulty": 3
        },
        {
            "id": "10",
            "question": "The functions f and g are defined as f(x) = 3/x and g(x) = 2x+7. What is the value of f(g(2))?",
            "type": "multiple_choice",
            "options": [
                "1.2",
                "3",
                "4.2",
                "0.6"
            ],
            "correct_answer": "0.6",
            "whyCorrectAnswer": "First find g(2) = 2*2 + 7 = 11. Then substitute 11 into f(x) to get f(g(2)) = 3 / 11 = 0.6.",
            "difficulty": 4
        },
        {
            "id": "11",
            "question": "If f(x)=x^2 - 4x + 3, and g(x)=2x - 1, what is the value of g(f(2))? ",
            "type": "multiple_choice",
            "options": [
                "3",
                "-5",
                "5",
                "-3"
            ],
            "correct_answer": "-5",
            "whyCorrectAnswer": "Substitute x=2 into f(x) to find f(2)=2. Then put x=f(2)=2 into g(x) to get g(f(2)) = 2*2 -1 = -5.",
            "difficulty": 3
        }
    ]
}